<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>azure on Blog</title>
    <link>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/tags/azure/</link>
    <description>Recent content in azure on Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 19:39:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/tags/azure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Compare Resources From Terraform Plan</title>
      <link>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/compare-resources-from-terraform-plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 19:39:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/compare-resources-from-terraform-plan/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a link to a repo I created today, that will be used to host examples of all challenges I encounter that relate to Terraform.
In this particular sample, I need to list out all those resources that will be created using Terraform where we do not have a state file. The product of this will be added to sheets, by Resource Group, in an Excel spreadsheet. Each sheet is an Azure Resource Group.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Conditionally Include a Nuget Package</title>
      <link>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/how-to-conditionally-include-a-nuget-package/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2022 20:58:53 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/how-to-conditionally-include-a-nuget-package/</guid>
      <description>The context I have implemented a solution that as it&amp;rsquo;s primary objective iterates through a sequence of HTTP Requests and page interactions. With sequencing through these steps regularly it gives the support team the maximum amount of time to react to an outage. This outage can be isolated to this particular service, or can originate from any of it&amp;rsquo;s downstream dependencies.
To help with the automation of these steps, I&amp;rsquo;m using Selenium and in particular, it&amp;rsquo;s headless browser capability in conjunction with ChromeDriver.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Grass Is Rarely Greener</title>
      <link>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/the-grass-is-rarely-greener/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 18:27:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/the-grass-is-rarely-greener/</guid>
      <description>I recently had a conversation that stirred up some surpressed memories. The conversation was related to moving to a different cloud vendor. That journey didn&amp;rsquo;t work out so well for me and the company I was working for at the time. Sadly, that company stopped trading and I don&amp;rsquo;t think it&amp;rsquo;s that much of a leap to link that journey to the demise of that company. Hopefully, now the title of this post is starting to make more sense?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Defender for Cloud</title>
      <link>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/azure-defender-for-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 11:57:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/azure-defender-for-cloud/</guid>
      <description>Defender for Cloud Containers Setting up Defender for Cloud Containers to work with your CICD pipeline is quick and uncomplicated. I do not walk through these set up steps in this post. For that, you can follow those few steps here in this Microsoft post instead ➡ Setup. The goal of this post is to highlight a few areas of interest and to share my opinions on this feature. I have understandably obfuscated sensitive information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes on Windows</title>
      <link>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/kubernetes-on-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 10:20:26 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/kubernetes-on-windows/</guid>
      <description>This post is a reminder to me of what needs to be installed in order for a pod, created from a local image, that is to be served up via a kubernetes cluster, to be run from your local development environment.
What is Kubernetes and why is it so important? &amp;ldquo;Kubernetes is a portable, extensible, open-source platform for managing containerized workloads and services, that facilitates both declarative configuration and automation. It has a large, rapidly growing ecosystem.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
