<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog</title>
    <link>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language><atom:link href="http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>.NET Aspire and Redis</title>
      <link>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/dotnet-aspire-and-redis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2024 09:41:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/dotnet-aspire-and-redis/</guid>
      <description>First look into .NET Aspire I decided to give .NET Aspire a try. I&amp;rsquo;m yet to watch an online tutorial but I did watch its announcement a few months ago. At the time I did think YAGNI. For me, it didn&amp;rsquo;t make much sense. Either that, or it just wasn&amp;rsquo;t being explained well enough. Enthusiasm alone isn&amp;rsquo;t enough to promote a new tool. Since then, I’ve seen many tweets. So, over the last month or so, I’ve gradually grasped its raison d’être.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 3rd Wave of Cloud Computing</title>
      <link>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/the-3rd-wave-of-cloud-computing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 19:26:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/the-3rd-wave-of-cloud-computing/</guid>
      <description>That&amp;rsquo;s quite an opening statement, isn&amp;rsquo;t it?
As a reminder, the 1st and 2nd waves were Virtual Machines and Containers, respectively.
Warning, profound statement inbound…
The Docker cofounder, Solomon Hykes, said this in 2019
&amp;ldquo;If WASM+WASI existed in 2008, we wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have needed to create Docker. That&amp;rsquo;s how important it is. WebAssembly on the server is the future of computing.&amp;rdquo; - QuoteI think we need to let this sink in for a few moments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compare Resources From Terraform Plan</title>
      <link>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/compare-resources-from-terraform-plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 19:39:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/compare-resources-from-terraform-plan/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a link to a repo I created today, that will be used to host examples of all challenges I encounter that relate to Terraform.
In this particular sample, I need to list out all those resources that will be created using Terraform where we do not have a state file. The product of this will be added to sheets, by Resource Group, in an Excel spreadsheet. Each sheet is an Azure Resource Group.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Error NETSDK1045</title>
      <link>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/error-NETSDK1045/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 20:22:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/error-NETSDK1045/</guid>
      <description>Error NETSDK1045 The current .NET SDK does not support targeting .NET 6.0 A colleague had Visual Studio shout this (see 👇) at him when he loaded up a FunctionsApp project. He received this error twice as the second project was the unit tests for the FunctionsApp.
Error NETSDK1045 The current .NET SDK does not support targeting .NET 6.0. Either target .NET 5.0 or lower, or use a version of the .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Write Clipboard to File</title>
      <link>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/how-to-write-clipboard-to-file/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 17:21:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/how-to-write-clipboard-to-file/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever wondered how to persist your clipboard to disk? Wonder no more&amp;hellip;
To get started, copy a random sentence into your clipboard like so:
Set-Clipboard -Value &amp;#34;This is being copied into clipboard&amp;#34; Let&amp;rsquo;s confirm the contents of the clipboard, like so:
Get-Clipboard output:
This is being copied into clipboard We&amp;rsquo;ll now persist the same cliboard to a file, like so:
Get-Clipboard | Out-File -FilePath clipboard.txt To confirm the contents of this file, we type:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Conditionally Include a Nuget Package</title>
      <link>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/how-to-conditionally-include-a-nuget-package/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2022 20:58:53 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/how-to-conditionally-include-a-nuget-package/</guid>
      <description>The context I have implemented a solution that as it&amp;rsquo;s primary objective iterates through a sequence of HTTP Requests and page interactions. With sequencing through these steps regularly it gives the support team the maximum amount of time to react to an outage. This outage can be isolated to this particular service, or can originate from any of it&amp;rsquo;s downstream dependencies.
To help with the automation of these steps, I&amp;rsquo;m using Selenium and in particular, it&amp;rsquo;s headless browser capability in conjunction with ChromeDriver.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.NET Stack, Heap and Boxing</title>
      <link>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/dotnet-stack-and-heap/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 08:38:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/dotnet-stack-and-heap/</guid>
      <description>This week I have been investigating how to reduce memory allocation in a few HTTP APIs. I won&amp;rsquo;t go into any explicit work-related examples here but I will touch on facets relating to this effort.
Let&amp;rsquo;s start off by looking at Reference Types and Value types and how they get allocated into the Heap. I will also touch on concepts such as boxing and GC pressure.
Let me start off with some facts:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Grass Is Rarely Greener</title>
      <link>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/the-grass-is-rarely-greener/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 18:27:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/the-grass-is-rarely-greener/</guid>
      <description>I recently had a conversation that stirred up some surpressed memories. The conversation was related to moving to a different cloud vendor. That journey didn&amp;rsquo;t work out so well for me and the company I was working for at the time. Sadly, that company stopped trading and I don&amp;rsquo;t think it&amp;rsquo;s that much of a leap to link that journey to the demise of that company. Hopefully, now the title of this post is starting to make more sense?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nodejs Install E401</title>
      <link>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/nodejs-install-e401/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 16:54:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/nodejs-install-e401/</guid>
      <description>Today I created a simple nodeJS Azure Functions Applicaiton to start building out a PoC and when I tried to install it&amp;rsquo;s dependencies like so:
npm install I got this little cherub back instead:
npm ERR! code E401
npm ERR! Incorrect or missing password.
npm ERR! If you were trying to login, change your password, create an
npm ERR! authentication token or enable two-factor authentication then
npm ERR! that means you likely typed your password in incorrectly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes Pod Disruption Budget and the Helm hasKey Function</title>
      <link>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/k8s-pdb/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 14:19:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/k8s-pdb/</guid>
      <description>Pod Disruption Budget When working with Kubernetes, one crucial component of configuration is known as a PDB (Pod Disruption Budget). A PDB will ensure your workload remains running when you work through a Voluntary Disruption.
What on earth is a Voluntary Disruption? A Voluntary Disruption is when you trigger an action that causes the disruption. For example, if you wish to upgrade a Minor AKS version or any action that recycles a Node Pool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding more Github Self-Hosted Runners</title>
      <link>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/github-self-hosted-runner/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 11:50:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/github-self-hosted-runner/</guid>
      <description>Adding more GitHub Self-Hosted Runners To help build out our numbers of GitHub Self-Hosted Runner, we took a shortcut and had cloned an existing Linux VM.
Unfortunately, the by-product of doing this resulted in (a) the clonee (source) Linux VM had their Self-Hosted hijacked by the new VM and (b) we had a Runner registered in GitHub that didn&amp;rsquo;t actually have a running runner - Offline 🤪.
Madness!
Ok, so what to do?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid Origins Http Traffic</title>
      <link>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/hybrid-origins-http-traffic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 17:25:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/hybrid-origins-http-traffic/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re migrating our on-premise workloads to Azure. This has presented several challenges. One of which is what I am covering specifically here in this post and that is &amp;hellip;
How to reduce code change effort?
This isn&amp;rsquo;t about updating runtimes, this is about having workloads spread across different platforms that need to talk to each other (with some HTTP chaining 👀). It is not uncommon for one HTTP API to need to talk to another HTTP API.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>K8s Selectors and Labels</title>
      <link>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/k8s-selectors-and-labels/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 13:30:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/k8s-selectors-and-labels/</guid>
      <description>Right, what&amp;rsquo;s the deal with all the labels and metadata in a Deployment manifest?!!!!
Take this example:
apiVersion: apps/v1 kind: Deployment metadata: namespace: default name: nginx-deployment labels: app: nginx spec: replicas: 3 selector: matchLabels: app: nginx foo: baa template: metadata: labels: app: nginx foo: baa spec: containers: - name: nginx image: nginx:1.14.2 ports: - containerPort: 80 Here, we see metadata twice, and also there&amp;rsquo;s mention of matchLabels in selector??? What does it all mean?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Defender for Cloud</title>
      <link>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/azure-defender-for-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 11:57:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/azure-defender-for-cloud/</guid>
      <description>Defender for Cloud Containers Setting up Defender for Cloud Containers to work with your CICD pipeline is quick and uncomplicated. I do not walk through these set up steps in this post. For that, you can follow those few steps here in this Microsoft post instead ➡ Setup. The goal of this post is to highlight a few areas of interest and to share my opinions on this feature. I have understandably obfuscated sensitive information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Npm E401 and CERT_NOT_YET_VALID</title>
      <link>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/npm-issues-e401-cert_not_yet_valid/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 11:47:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/npm-issues-e401-cert_not_yet_valid/</guid>
      <description>Today a PR Merge resulted in a GHA failure. Sadly, this is not the only CICD pipeline to fail this year! This particular pipeline builds a NodeJS Image, pushes the image to ACR and deploys the service to a production Docker Swarm (on merge to main).
This was the error:
[3/7] RUN npm install:
#7 1.469 npm ERR! code E401
#7 1.470 npm ERR! Unable to authenticate, need: Bearer authorization_uri=https://login.windows.net/736f9f**-09-49-86**-b******31f407, Basic realm=&amp;ldquo;https://pkgsprodsu3weu.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Github Actions Workflow Env Vars</title>
      <link>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/github-actions-workflow-env-vars/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2022 15:13:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/github-actions-workflow-env-vars/</guid>
      <description>In my current role as Head of Cloud Platform, I am leading the technical effort of migrating our entire on-premise real-estate to Azure. Part of this mission, is to upgrade the runtimes of our applications, regardless of their current placement; IIS Web apps, Windows Services and Docker Swarm containers. I say &amp;ldquo;part of this mission&amp;rdquo; as another aspect of this migration is to create a new foundation for our platform - AKS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Runtimes</title>
      <link>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/runtimes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jan 2022 11:09:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/runtimes/</guid>
      <description>In my current role as Head of Cloud Platform, I am leading the technical effort of migrating our entire on-premise real-estate to Azure. Part of this mission, is to upgrade the runtimes of our applications, regardless of their current placement; IIS Web apps, Windows Services and Docker Swarm containers. I say &amp;ldquo;part of this mission&amp;rdquo; as another aspect of this migration is to create a new foundation for our platform - AKS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Permission Denied While Trying to Connect to the Docker Daemon Socket</title>
      <link>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/permission-denied-while-trying-to-connect-to-the-docker-daemon-socket/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 08:20:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/permission-denied-while-trying-to-connect-to-the-docker-daemon-socket/</guid>
      <description>Out of the blue today, my first day back after Christmas break, I got this when running a GH Actions Workflow on one of our Self-Hosted Linux Runners 😱:
Got permission denied while trying to connect to the Docker daemon socket at unix:///var/run/docker.sock: Get &amp;ldquo;http://%2Fvar%2Frun%2Fdocker.sock/v1.24/containers/json&#34;: dial unix /var/run/docker.sock: connect: permission deniedWe have several GitHub Self-Hosted Runners running on Linux and Windows O/S that produce, amongst other artefacts, Linux and Windows images.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First Outing With Dapr</title>
      <link>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/my-first-outing-with-dapr/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 09:54:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/my-first-outing-with-dapr/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR: Not as forgiving as I&amp;rsquo;d have liked &amp;hellip;
I was a speaker at a meet-up in Manchester in late 2020. I spoke about Dapr, Keda and the NestJS Framework. My talk topic was on &amp;ldquo;Writing less code - let your architecture and abstractions help with your *-cases&amp;rdquo;. The * in the title is a wildcard for use/edge/corner.
My code examples can be found here (includes both docker compose &amp;amp; Kubernetes manifests) - https://github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Use Kubernetes Configmap</title>
      <link>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/how-to-use-kubernetes-configmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Nov 2020 15:31:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/how-to-use-kubernetes-configmap/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s a ton of material out there on how to use a ConfigMap. In this post I will provide a recap on the basics then I drill into how to protect your secrets!
There are a few ways to create a configMap. Here, I cover just two of these ways;--from-env-file and &amp;ndash;from-literal. I won&amp;rsquo;t cover options like from volume.
How to create a ConfigMap from a literal To create a configMap from literals and from the command line, you would type this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nodejs Container Restart Policy</title>
      <link>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/nodejs-container-restart-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 16:36:35 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/nodejs-container-restart-policy/</guid>
      <description>If by accident to deploy a solution using the Node.js Cluster API and do not fork exited processes then the following docker-compose restart_policy will not help you:
deploy: restart_policy: condition: on-failure If you&amp;rsquo;re using the Cluster API to schedule tasks across your processes, and all forked processes die, then the docker engine will just assume you&amp;rsquo;ve gracefully shutdown.
Take this code for example, you will see that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t fork another process and therefore, at some point it will no longer process any anything:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to run the Apache Ignite Agent with an Ignite.NET Core Server Node</title>
      <link>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/apache-ignite-running-agent-with-dotnetcore-server-node/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 13:48:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/apache-ignite-running-agent-with-dotnetcore-server-node/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve recently been researching into Apache Ignite. Apache Ignite is an in-memory, memory-centric, distributed database, caching and processing platform for transactional, analytical, and streaming workloads.
So why the post? Well, with using .NET Core, I have run into one or two challenges that I have had to work through. One of which involves the Agent. I feel it is important to share with you how I get beyond this issue. It may save you a lot of time if you&amp;rsquo;re an Apache Ignite noob like me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terraform Get Values</title>
      <link>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/terraform-get-values/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 13:42:59 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/terraform-get-values/</guid>
      <description>With not wanting to have hard coded values pushed to a project&amp;rsquo;s code repository, and an antiquated way to derive Azure Service Principal credentials, I set about exploring ways on accomplishing this with this in mind using Terraform.
Attempt 1 Here ins my first attempt, I load all permutations into map variables. I use an environment variable as an indexer to the appropriate map value:
provider &amp;#34;azurerm&amp;#34; { version = &amp;#34;=2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Certificates</title>
      <link>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/digital-certificates/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 12:57:32 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/digital-certificates/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to put some notes down on digital certificates, signing and JWT for some time now. I find there are plenty of confusing terms involved in this area, plus a few nuances that have added to my personal confusion. I feel it now important to document these before I forget and move on [to another project].
So, what&amp;rsquo;s triggered this post? Well, one of many tasks I&amp;rsquo;m involved in [juggling] evolves SSO (single sign on).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unit testing and mocking fs.ReadFileSync</title>
      <link>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/jest-fs-readFileSync/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 07:32:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/jest-fs-readFileSync/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;d just ran npm run test in a newly created package I&amp;rsquo;d added to a monorepo (lerna) I&amp;rsquo;d created for a project I was working on that integrates with Twilio Sync, RabbitMQ, Twilio TaskRouter and MSSQL, and I go this:
*******************************consumers\packages\eda [CRMBROK-233 +0 ~2 -0 !]&amp;gt; npm run test &amp;gt; @cf247/eda@1.0.2 test *******************************consumers\packages\eda &amp;gt; jest FAIL __tests__/eda.test.js ● Test suite failed to run ENOENT: no such file or directory, open &amp;#39;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes on Windows</title>
      <link>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/kubernetes-on-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 10:20:26 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/kubernetes-on-windows/</guid>
      <description>This post is a reminder to me of what needs to be installed in order for a pod, created from a local image, that is to be served up via a kubernetes cluster, to be run from your local development environment.
What is Kubernetes and why is it so important? &amp;ldquo;Kubernetes is a portable, extensible, open-source platform for managing containerized workloads and services, that facilitates both declarative configuration and automation. It has a large, rapidly growing ecosystem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modern-ish Javascript</title>
      <link>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/modern-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 10:16:22 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/modern-javascript/</guid>
      <description>This post includes a few notes on ECMA language features that I like as well as some info on memory leaking. I have no doubt that it will read disjointed; I started this eons ago and only now have I decided to publish it.
A simple reminder of what Node.js is &amp;hellip;it is a set of APIs wrapped around the V8 Engine (written in c++) and is a high-performance JavaScript and WebAssembly engine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How do I mentor?</title>
      <link>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/mentoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 06:09:14 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/mentoring/</guid>
      <description>I have written this post to document my experiences of mentoring. I have mentored front-end engineers, back-end engineers and UX designers. I have had the pleasure of helping others as well as learning one of two things about myself along this journey too. If ever you get the opportunity to be a mentor, I recommend you jump at the opportunity. It is a self-rewarding experience.
So, what is mentoring?&amp;hellip;
The definition of Mentoring is the act of advising or training (someone, especially a younger colleague).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Good Engineering - Principles</title>
      <link>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/principles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 20:09:14 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.garrardkitchen.com/posts/principles/</guid>
      <description>I have written this post as a method to document what I see as the basics, foundations if you will, for good engineering. Undoubtedly if you are a seasoned engineer, you will recognised all of these principles, less so, if you&amp;rsquo;re just starting out.
Most Engineers are fully versed in the foundations of writing quality, efficient, succinct and testable code. As a Principal Engineer, one of my responsibilities is to ensure that these (1) foundations are recognised by the engineers and (2) are adhered to by all engineers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
